Devnarayan Mandal

SENIOR ACCOUNTANT

devnarayanmandal3_68q@indeedemail.com

+918100906835

A Competent profession with around 7 YEARS EXPEREINCE AS AN ACCOUNTANT with Trading company & C.A Firm and to secure a responsible and challenging position where my education and experience can be fully utilized and where I can make a significant contribution to my seniors through work.

Work Experience

Senior Accountant

VASTRAMAY - New Delhi, Delhi September 2018 to Present

I am currently working in VASTRAMAY as an Senior Accountant and fulfill the all Responsibilities where Filling online GST Return, TDS Computation and payment online, preparation TDS return, all Day to Day accounting in Tally ERP 9 Like, sale, purchases, job charges, Bank reconciliation, stock maintenance and making the stock report and doing all banking work, preparation of profit & loss a/c and making the balance sheet, and keeping record in Tally ERP 9,

- 1. Making the invoice by Tally ERP-9
- 2) Making GRN for Purchases
- 3) Book sale order & purchases order
- 4) Computation of GST& Filling Online return
- 5) TDS Computation and payment Filling Return Online
- 6) Generate e-way bill under GST
- 7) Stock maintain & Prepare salary sheet monthly

ACCOUNTANT

SNG MICRONS PVT.LTD June 2016 to August 2018

I Had worked in SNG MICRONS PVT. LTD. as an accountant and fulfill the all Responsibilities where Handling sale Tax assessment and Filling online Return VAT, CST, GST all Day to Day accounting in Tally ERP 9 Like, sale, purchases, Bank reconciliation, stock maintenance and making the stock report and doing all banking work, preparation of profit & loss a/c and making the balance sheet, and keeping record in Tally ERP 9,

Accounts Executive

AAYUSH AGARWAL & CO July 2013 to May 2016

I had worked as an. Accounts exe. and my responsibilities are, calculating, Filling of the return Online, and fill up to the form, Preparing of TDS challan, Accounting in Tally ERP9, finalized of accounts, Handling sales tax Assessment, VAT, CST, Return filling, secretarial & documentation in Word, excel,

internet and presentation in, Co-ordinator to finalize the annual report, managing the preparation and Maintenance of statutory books of accounts, inventory records, reconciliation statements, financial statements

All Day to Day accounting in Tally ERP 9 Like, sale, purchases, Bank reconciliation, stock maintenance and making the stock report and doing all banking work, preparation of profit & loss a/c and making the balance sheet, and keeping record in Tally ERP 9,

Education

Bachelor's in ACCOUNTS

June 2011

Bihar Board

2008

Accounting Licenses

ICWA SEMI QUALIFIED

Expires: June 2013

State: DE

Skills / IT Skills

- Preparing and maintaining statutory books of accounts viz, journal, ledger, cash book and subsidiaries in compliance with time & accuracy norms. (6 years)
- Presenting a true and fair view of the financial position of the company by preparing financial statements viz, P/L account and Balance sheet.
- · Conceptualizing, implementing and supervising general ledger and financial reporting processes
- Verifying Monthly Bank Statement, Preparing BRS (Bank Reconciliation Statement)
- Conducting Verification of general book of accounts to detect any possible fraud.
- Co-ordinating with the auditors for audit & preparing monthly/quarterly/yearly schedule for audit.
- Maintain up to date position of Sundry Debtor and Creditor.
- Accounting of inter unit transfer, preparation of debit/credit note.
- · Conducting physical verification of stock in trade with stock in books at site
- · Finalization of Accounts
- Audit the books of company, furnishing report & finalizing it. TAXATION
- Computation of GST and filling online return.
- Handling the Sale Tax Assessments VAT, CST filling Return online..
- Computation of TDS and making payment online. Filling Return online
- Reconcile GSTR-2A with Books of Accounts
- · Basic concept of ESI, PF
- Computation of Income Tax of Individual, proprietorship business MANAGEMENT
- Maintain ratio Analysis i.e Gross Profit, Net Profit, Closing Stock & Expenses Ratio.

- Maintain standard ratio of Current and working capital ratio ..
- Monitoring of timely deposition of all statutory dues, filling of returns and their assessment which includes Sales tax, Service tax, Income tax and etc. In depth Computerized Financial Accounting knowledge with all the leading Financial Accounting Software. (Tally all Versions, excel)
- · Good knowledge of computer operation with Dos, Windows 7, XP and Vista
- Ms-Word, Excel, and Internet operation (Like Internet Chatting, Email Creating, Internet browsing, downloading etc.)
- Good knowledge of Software Installing, Formatting, Scanning etc.
- Proficient & got reasonable speed in Computerized Billed.
- Working knowledge of TALLY, GST, TDS, ACCOUNT FINALISATION Accounting, Organizational Skills, high computer literacy, Hard working, Punctuality and discipline and honesty.
- · Bookkeeping
- · Accounts Payable
- Excel
- accounting
- tally